<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Continuous Improvement on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/continuous-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Continuous Improvement on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/continuous-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Demand Planning Behaviours</title>
      <link>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</guid>
      <description>What’s better; making the wrong decision for the right reasons or making the right decision for the wrong reasons? If it’s one-off, then the right decision for the wrong reasons (also known as a fluke), is likely to receive plaudits. However, if it’s part of a decision making process recurring every month, such as sales forecasting, then I’ll back the wrong decision for the right reasons (also known as bad luck) every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach to New Product Forecasting</title>
      <link>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Pure Blonde Lager was easily the most successful new product launch in my time at Foster’s Group. The story goes that the concept was rushed through as senior management was concerned with the slim pickings in the new product pipeline. Almost immediately from when this lo-carb beer was launched, sales exceeded forecasts, leaving almost everyone in the supply chain scrambling to keep up. And it wasn’t just the warehouses that were screaming for more stock, it was the bottling lines, brewing facilities and packaging suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agile opportunity for Demand Planning Improvements</title>
      <link>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</guid>
      <description>Demand planning team “going OK / not going OK”!
A demand planner was recounting how her team was travelling OK but she felt that there was scope for significant improvement.
For one thing, she felt that her team’s stakeholders didn’t really understand what the team did “beneath the bonnet” and would struggle to explain what value that they added to the business. There was, certainly, general satisfaction in the team’s output and people would say that, from the outside, that they were working well together, but that also reflected that stakeholders were somewhat unaware of the internal machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>