<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stakeholder management on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/stakeholder-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stakeholder management on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/stakeholder-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Reviews for Process Improvement: A Retrium Case Study</title>
      <link>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last week, my team applied a new approach with great success to our performance retrospective. The approach worked so well that I’m standing up and evangelising the approach for a wider range of teams than those like our’s who apply Agile.
 Retrospective Goals and Objectives The goal of our sprint (i.e. our 3-week activity cycle) retrospective is to improve our systems and processes to drive business value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making MAPE More Meaningful</title>
      <link>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</guid>
      <description>“You can’t manage what you can’t measure”, which is why it’s important for businesses to measure forecast accuracy. For those unaware, MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error) is one of the three most common forecast accuracy measures along with bias and MSE. It is also used as a proxy for measuring the demand planning value-add in an FMCG businesses. That is, when the MAPE score is favourable (low), then it is assumed that demand planning’s value-add for a business must be high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is best: Finance, Supply or Sales?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</guid>
      <description>Which is the best department to oversee Demand Planning: Sales, Supply or Finance? This question, often asked, lends itself to my experience of at least 2 years under each of these departments within FMCG businesses.
 Finance from 2006 to 2008
 Supply from 2008 to 2011
 Sales from 2011 to 2015  This blog post, mixing my own observations with my own opinions, covers the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agile opportunity for Demand Planning Improvements</title>
      <link>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</guid>
      <description>Demand planning team “going OK / not going OK”!
A demand planner was recounting how her team was travelling OK but she felt that there was scope for significant improvement.
For one thing, she felt that her team’s stakeholders didn’t really understand what the team did “beneath the bonnet” and would struggle to explain what value that they added to the business. There was, certainly, general satisfaction in the team’s output and people would say that, from the outside, that they were working well together, but that also reflected that stakeholders were somewhat unaware of the internal machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>