<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecast on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/forecast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecast on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/forecast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting During a Pandemic - IBF Webinar</title>
      <link>/2020/03/forecasting-during-a-pandemic-ibf-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/forecasting-during-a-pandemic-ibf-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction COVID-19 presents demand planning with plenty of challenges, though it also might present opportunities. An example given in the introduction to this webinar was of Isaac Newton, a mere college student at Cambridge University when the campus closed in 1665 due to the Black Plague. While practicing the 1600’s version of social distancing, the curious and contemplative Newton formed his groundbreaking ideas on calculus, optics and gravity. These ideas were converted into theory when he returned to the reopened university in 1665.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Reviews for Process Improvement: A Retrium Case Study</title>
      <link>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last week, my team applied a new approach with great success to our performance retrospective. The approach worked so well that I’m standing up and evangelising the approach for a wider range of teams than those like our’s who apply Agile.
 Retrospective Goals and Objectives The goal of our sprint (i.e. our 3-week activity cycle) retrospective is to improve our systems and processes to drive business value.
The objectives or our retrospectives are to identify what from our previous sprint that worked well and what didn’t work well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boutique forecasting for boutique beer</title>
      <link>/2020/01/boutique-forecasting-for-boutique-beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/boutique-forecasting-for-boutique-beer/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Boutique brewery numbers have exploded in Australia in the past 2 decades. So much so that the growth in demand for boutique brews has led corporate brewing companies, CUB, Lion, Asahi and Coca Cola Amatil, to acquire and establish their own boutique beer brands. Data taken from http://craftbeerreviewer.com/the-brewery-list/ shows that 701 boutique brewing brands now operate around Australia.
While I’m yet to find data on the historical growth of craft beers in Australia, Goldstein Research forecasts the Australian market to reach $345 million by 2025 with CAGR of over 5%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making MAPE More Meaningful</title>
      <link>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</guid>
      <description>“You can’t manage what you can’t measure”, which is why it’s important for businesses to measure forecast accuracy. For those unaware, MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error) is one of the three most common forecast accuracy measures along with bias and MSE. It is also used as a proxy for measuring the demand planning value-add in an FMCG businesses. That is, when the MAPE score is favourable (low), then it is assumed that demand planning’s value-add for a business must be high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Demand Planning Behaviours</title>
      <link>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</guid>
      <description>What’s better; making the wrong decision for the right reasons or making the right decision for the wrong reasons? If it’s one-off, then the right decision for the wrong reasons (also known as a fluke), is likely to receive plaudits. However, if it’s part of a decision making process recurring every month, such as sales forecasting, then I’ll back the wrong decision for the right reasons (also known as bad luck) every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach to New Product Forecasting</title>
      <link>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Pure Blonde Lager was easily the most successful new product launch in my time at Foster’s Group. The story goes that the concept was rushed through as senior management was concerned with the slim pickings in the new product pipeline. Almost immediately from when this lo-carb beer was launched, sales exceeded forecasts, leaving almost everyone in the supply chain scrambling to keep up. And it wasn’t just the warehouses that were screaming for more stock, it was the bottling lines, brewing facilities and packaging suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is best: Finance, Supply or Sales?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</guid>
      <description>Which is the best department to oversee Demand Planning: Sales, Supply or Finance? This question, often asked, lends itself to my experience of at least 2 years under each of these departments within FMCG businesses.
 Finance from 2006 to 2008
 Supply from 2008 to 2011
 Sales from 2011 to 2015  This blog post, mixing my own observations with my own opinions, covers the following areas:
The role of demand planning Impressions while under Finance, Supply and Sales Which department should oversee demand planning A key consideration to appointing a demand manager The final word - Sales  Demand Planning’s role</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forecasts are deliberately wrong&#34;</title>
      <link>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</guid>
      <description>“Forecasts are deliberately wrong”
Whoa! This confronting remark shot back at me when telling a data science colleague that I am an experienced Demand Manager. A part of my shock came from knowing deep down that I could see where he was coming from despite always striving towards achieving a “50/50” forecast; i.e. a forecast with a 50% chance of sitting too high balanced by a 50% chance of sitting too low.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>