<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Reviews for Process Improvement: A Retrium Case Study</title>
      <link>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My team applied a new approach with great success to our performance retrospective last week. The approach worked so well that I’m standing up and evangalising the approach for a wider range of teams than those like our’s who apply Agile.
 Retrospective Goals and Objectives The goal of our performance retrospective is to improve our systems and processes to drive business value.
The objectives or our retrospectives are to identify what from our previous sprint that worked well and what didn’t work well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boutique forecasting for boutique beer</title>
      <link>/2020/01/boutique-forecasting-for-boutique-beer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/boutique-forecasting-for-boutique-beer/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Boutique brewery numbers have exploded in Australia in the past 2 decades. So much so that the growth in demand for boutique brews has led corporate brewing companies, CUB, Lion, Asahi and Coca Cola Amatil, to acquire and establish their own boutique beer brands. Data taken from http://craftbeerreviewer.com/the-brewery-list/ shows that 701 boutique brewing brands now operate around Australia.
While I’m yet to find data on the historical growth of craft beers in Australia, Goldstein Research forecasts the Australian market to reach $345 million by 2025 with CAGR of over 5%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making MAPE More Meaningful</title>
      <link>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</guid>
      <description>“You can’t manage what you can’t measure”, which is why it’s important for businesses to measure forecast accuracy. For those unaware, MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error) is one of the three most common forecast accuracy measures along with bias and MSE. It is also used as a proxy for measuring the demand planning value-add in an FMCG businesses. That is, when the MAPE score is favourable (low), then it is assumed that demand planning’s value-add for a business must be high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Demand Planning Behaviours</title>
      <link>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</guid>
      <description>What’s better; making the wrong decision for the right reasons or making the right decision for the wrong reasons? If it’s one-off, then the right decision for the wrong reasons (also known as a fluke), is likely to receive plaudits. However, if it’s part of a decision making process recurring every month, such as sales forecasting, then I’ll back the wrong decision for the right reasons (also known as bad luck) every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is best: Finance, Supply or Sales?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</guid>
      <description>Which is the best department to oversee Demand Planning: Sales, Supply or Finance? This question, often asked, lends itself to my experience of at least 2 years under each of these departments within FMCG businesses.
 Finance from 2006 to 2008
 Supply from 2008 to 2011
 Sales from 2011 to 2015  This blog post, mixing my own observations with my own opinions, covers the following areas:
The role of demand planning Impressions while under Finance, Supply and Sales Which department should oversee demand planning A key consideration to appointing a demand manager The final word - Sales  Demand Planning’s role</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agile opportunity for Demand Planning Improvements</title>
      <link>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</guid>
      <description>Demand planning team “going OK / not going OK”!
A demand planner was recounting how her team was travelling OK but she felt that there was scope for significant improvement.
For one thing, she felt that her team’s stakeholders didn’t really understand what the team did “beneath the bonnet” and would struggle to explain what value that they added to the business. There was, certainly, general satisfaction in the team’s output and people would say that, from the outside, that they were working well together, but that also reflected that stakeholders were somewhat unaware of the internal machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>