<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is best: Finance, Supply or Sales?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</guid>
      <description>Which is the best department to oversee Demand Planning: Sales, Supply or Finance? This question, often asked, lends itself to my experience of at least 2 years under each of these departments within a variety of FMCG businesses.
 Finance from 2006 to 2008
 Supply from 2008 to 2011
 Sales from 2011 to 2015  This blog post, mixing my own observations with my own opinions, covers the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agile opportunity for Demand Planning Improvements</title>
      <link>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/the-agile-opportunity-for-demand-planning-improvements/</guid>
      <description>Demand planning team “going OK / not going OK”!
A demand planner was recounting how her team was travelling OK but she felt that there was scope for significant improvement.
For one thing, she felt that her team’s stakeholders didn’t really understand what the team did “beneath the bonnet” and would struggle to explain what value that they added to the business. There was, certainly, general satisfaction in the team’s output and people would say that, from the outside, that they were working well together, but that also reflected that stakeholders were somewhat unaware of the internal machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forecasts are deliberately wrong&#34;</title>
      <link>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</guid>
      <description>“Forecasts are deliberately wrong”
Whoa! This confronting remark shot back at me when telling a data science colleague that I am an experienced Demand Manager. A part of my shock came from knowing deep down that I could see where he was coming from despite always striving towards achieving a “50/50” forecast; i.e. a forecast with a 50% chance of sitting too high balanced by a 50% chance of sitting too low.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>