<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncertainty on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/uncertainty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncertainty on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/uncertainty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making MAPE More Meaningful</title>
      <link>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</guid>
      <description>“You can’t manage what you can’t measure”, which is why it’s important for businesses to measure forecast accuracy. For those unaware, MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error) is one of the three most common forecast accuracy measures along with bias and MSE. It is also a proxy for measuring the demand planning value-add in an FMCG businesses. That is, when the MAPE score is favourable (low), then demand planning’s value-add for a business must be high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Demand Planning Behaviours</title>
      <link>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/measuring-demand-planning-behaviours/</guid>
      <description>What’s better; making the wrong decision for the right reasons or making the right decision for the wrong reasons? If it’s one-off, then the right decision for the wrong reasons (also known as a fluke), is likely to receive plaudits. However, if it’s part of a decision making process recurring every month, such as sales forecasting, then I’ll back the wrong decision for the right reasons (also known as bad luck) every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Approach to New Product Forecasting</title>
      <link>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/new-approach-to-new-product-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Pure Blonde Lager was easily the most successful new product launch in my time at Foster’s Group. The story goes that the concept was rushed through as senior management was concerned with the slim pickings in the new product pipeline. Almost immediately from when this lo-carb beer was launched, sales exceeded forecasts, leaving almost everyone in the supply chain scrambling to keep up. And it wasn’t just the warehouses that were screaming for more stock, it was the bottling lines, brewing facilities and packaging suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forecasts are deliberately wrong&#34;</title>
      <link>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/forecasts-are-deliberately-wrong/</guid>
      <description>“Forecasts are deliberately wrong”
Whoa! This confronting remark shot back at me when telling a data science colleague that I am an experienced Demand Manager. A part of my shock came from knowing deep down that I could see where he was coming from despite always striving towards achieving a “50/50” forecast; i.e. a forecast with a 50% chance of sitting too high balanced by a 50% chance of sitting too low.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>