<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supply on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</title>
    <link>/tags/supply/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supply on Making 50-50 Demand Forecasts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/supply/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting During a Pandemic - IBF Webinar</title>
      <link>/2020/03/forecasting-during-a-pandemic-ibf-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/forecasting-during-a-pandemic-ibf-webinar/</guid>
      <description>Introduction COVID-19 presents demand planning with plenty of challenges, though it also might present opportunities. An example given in the introduction to this webinar was of Isaac Newton, a mere college student at Cambridge University when the campus closed in 1665 due to the Black Plague. While practicing the 1600’s version of social distancing, the curious and contemplative Newton formed his groundbreaking ideas on calculus, optics and gravity. These ideas were converted into theory when he returned to the reopened university in 1665.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective Reviews for Process Improvement: A Retrium Case Study</title>
      <link>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/retrospective-reviews-for-process-improvement-a-retrium-case-study/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last week, my team applied a new approach with great success to our performance retrospective. The approach worked so well that I’m standing up and evangelising the approach for a wider range of teams than those like our’s who apply Agile.
 Retrospective Goals and Objectives The goal of our sprint (i.e. our 3-week activity cycle) retrospective is to improve our systems and processes to drive business value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making MAPE More Meaningful</title>
      <link>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/making-mape-more-meaningful/</guid>
      <description>“You can’t manage what you can’t measure”, which is why it’s important for businesses to measure forecast accuracy. For those unaware, MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error) is one of the three most common forecast accuracy measures along with bias and MSE. It is also used as a proxy for measuring the demand planning value-add in an FMCG businesses. That is, when the MAPE score is favourable (low), then it is assumed that demand planning’s value-add for a business must be high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is best: Finance, Supply or Sales?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/who-is-best-finance-supply-or-sales/</guid>
      <description>Which is the best department to oversee Demand Planning: Sales, Supply or Finance? This question, often asked, lends itself to my experience of at least 2 years under each of these departments within FMCG businesses.
 Finance from 2006 to 2008
 Supply from 2008 to 2011
 Sales from 2011 to 2015  This blog post, mixing my own observations with my own opinions, covers the following areas:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>